A Guide to the Papers of Thomas Taylor Hammond 1949-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series V Papers written by scholars for conferences
  - Hoover Conference: "Fifty Years of Communism" 1967 October (Box-folder 25:7)
    Paper: The Soviet Economy: Retrospect and Prospect, G. Warren Nutter (University of Virginia); Paper: The Democratic Challenge to Communism, Sidney Hook (New York University); Paper: The Bases and Development of the Soviet Polity, Leonard Schapiro (University of London)
  - Conference: Institue for the Study of the USSR; Paper: The Political Aspects of the 21st Congress, Michael T. Florinsky 1959 April 4 (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Kennan Institute Conference on USSR and Marxist Revolutions 1986 September 25-26 (Box-folder 25:9)
    Paper: The USSR and Leftist Movements in Central America, W. Raymond Duncan (State University of New York College at Brockport and Georgetown University); Paper: Soviet Policy in the Third World: A net Assessment, William E. Grifith (MIT); Paper: Marxist-Leninist Insurgencies in the Third World: Historical U.S. Responses, William J. Taylor, Jr. (Georgetown University Center for Strategic and International Studies).
  - Listing of Conferences n.d. (Box-folder 25:10)
  - (Nationalities Conference Papers) Nationalism and the Soviet Union Conference: Implications for the Future 1968 Sept. 4-5 (Box-folder 25:11)
    Paper: The Ethnic Scene in the Soviet Union: The View of the Dictatorship, John A. Armstrong from Chapter 1 of the Ethnic Minorities in the Soviet Union; Background paper: Some Economic Aspects of Soviet Multi- Nationality; Paper: Resources Available at RL on Soviet Nationality Problems, Madeleine Manea; Paper: Ukrainian National Tensions, [Vsevolod] Holubnichy.
  - Proceedings of the Low-Intensity Warfare Conference, sponsored by the Department of Defense, Caspar W. Weinberger 1968 January 14-15 (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Research Conference on Communist Revolutions (St. Croix, V.I.) 1973 January 24-28 (Box-folder 25:13)
    Paper: Memory, Opportunity, and Strategy in Peasant Revolutions: The Case of North China, John Wilson Lewis (Stanford University); Paper: The Communist Movement and the Peasants: The Case of Korea, Se Hee Yoo (Columbia University); Paper: Traditional Modes and Communist Movements: The Place of Change in Protest and Insurrection, Rex Mortimer (University of Sidney); Paper: The 1971 Ceylonese Uprising: An Ecological Interpretaton of Its Origins and Fate, Robert N. Kearney (Syracuse University).
  - Research Conference on Communist Revolutions 1973 January 24-28 (Box-folder 25:14)
    Paper: The Urban Bases of Communist Revolt in Malya, Michael Stenson (University of Auckland); Paper: Popular Protest and the Non-Revolutionary path to Communist Power, George O. Totten (University of Southern California); Paper: The Stages of the Chinese Communist Movement, Ying Mao Kau (Brown University).
  - Research and Analsis Deparment (Free Europe Press) Survey of Major Trends 1954 August 11 (Box-folder 25:15)
  - Russian Research Center-Harvard 1948-1974 (Box-folder 25:16)
    Paper: Soviet Central Asia: A Selected Bibliography by Joseph S.Berliner; Paper: Certain Aspects of Soviet Industrial Life Selected as Contributions toward a Theory on the Soviet Firm, Joseph S. Berliner; Paper: Eighty-Seven Errors Concerning Soviet Law, Harold J. Berman; Paper: Recent Impressions of the Soviet Scene, Theodore Shabad; Mr. Dallin, American Sovietology, and Problems of Communism, Abraham Brumberg.
  - Seminar on "Soviet National Security Decision Making" 1984 May 3 (Box-folder 26:1)
    Paper: The Role of the Soviet Military in Ntional Security Decision Making, Harriet Fast Scott
  - Southern Conference on slavic Studies (5th annual) 1966 Oct 21-22 (Box-folder 26:2)
    Paper: Changes in the Central Committee, CPSU, Yarolsav Bilinsky (University of Delaware)
  - Soviet Policy on the Third World Conference: University of Arizona 1987 January (Box-folder 26:3)
    Paper: Marching to Pretoria? Soviet Objectives in Southern Africa, Seth Singleton (Pacific University); Paper: Soviet-Latin American Economic Relations, Ruben Berrios; Paper-Soviet Policy in the Carribean and Central America: Opportunities and Constraints, Howard J. Wiarda; Paper: The Soviet Union and the Arab-Israeli Conflict, Dr. Robert O. Freedman and Peggy Meyerhoff Pearlstone
  - St. Anthony's College Oxford Conference 1957; 1990 (Box-folder 26:4)
    Paper: Changes in Soviet Society, Richard Pipes; Paper: IV World Confgress for Soviet and East European Studies Harrogate: New Thinking on the Soviet Political System, Archie Brown
  - Subcommittee-Far East and Pacific of the Committee on Foreign Affairs 1965 May 14 (Box-folder 26:5)
    Paper: Sino-Soviet Conflict and Its Implications, Robert Rupen
  - Paper: The Agony of Gorbachev: Immaculate Conception, Hugh Ragsdale n.d. (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Paper: The Apparatus of Power, Jerry F. Hough 1978 May (Box-folder 27:2)
  - Paper: The Attack Against 'Dogmatists' and 'Sectarians', Central Research Division of Radio Liberty n.d. (Box-folder 27:3)
  - Paper: Bolsheviks n.d. (Box-folder 27:4)
  - Paper: Comrades' Courts and Labor Discipline Since Brezhnev, Paul B. Stephan III 1985 (Box-folder 27:5)
  - Paper: Countering Covert Aggression, Office of the Under Secretary of Defense, Hosmer and Tanner 1986 January (Box-folder 27:6)
  - Paper:Emancipation of the Baltic Peasants in 1817-1819, J. George Longworth n.d. (Box-folder 27:7)
  - Paper: Foreign Area Specialist and Studies in the USSR, Gottemoeller and Langer 1983 January (Box-folder 27:8)
  - Paper: The Impact of Detente on the Ideological and Political Importance of Eastern Europe to the Soviet Union, Vernon V. Aspaturian n.d. (Box-folder 27:9)
  - Paper:Peter Arkadievich Stolypin: A Political Appraisal, Alfred Levin n.d. (Box-folder 27:10)
  - Paper: Power or Pawn? The Soviet Role in Vietnam, Dr. Daniel S. Papp 1986 September (Box-folder 27:11)
  - Paper: The Russian Worker' Movement on the Eve of the First World War, L. H. Haimson n.d. (Box-folder 27:12)
  - Paper: Some Comparisons Between the Russian and Chines 'Models', Donald S. Zagoria 1962 March (Box-folder 27:13)
  - Paper: Soviet Economic Law: The Paradox of Perestroyka, Paul B. Stephan III n.d. (Box-folder 27:14)
  - Paper: soviet Economic Reform: From Resurgence to Retrenchment? Gertrude E. Schroeder 1989 March (Box-folder 27:15)
  - Paper:Soviet Occupation Policy Toward Germany, 1945-1949, Barbara Ann Chotiner and John M. Atwell 1976 Spring (Box-folder 27:16)
  - Paper: Soviet Policies in Africa, Richard F. Staar 1987 January 7 (Box-folder 27:17)
  - Paper: Soviet Support of Third World Revolution: Political and Ideological Instruments, Herbert J. Ellison n.d. (Box-folder 27:18)
  - Paper: The Soviet Union and Southeast Asia: The Vietnam Connection, Sheldon W. Simon n.d. (Box-folder 27:19)
  - Paper: Successes and Failures in Soviet Policy Towards Marxist Revolutions in the Third World Since 1917, S. Neil Macfarlane n.d. (Box-folder 27:20)
  - Paper: Turkic National Tensions in the USSR, David Nissman n.d. (Box-folder 27:21)
  - Paper:USSR and Southern Arabia, Mark N. Katz n.d. (Box-folder 27:22)
  - Paper:Vladimir N. Kokovtsev and the Russian Duma, 1911-1914, David R. Costello n.d. (Box-folder 27:23)
- Series VI Papers by Students-Restricted
  - Agriculture n.d. (Box-folder 28:1)
  - Agriculture 1975 May 23 (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Alexander II Reforms 1963; n.d. (Box-folder 28:3)
  - American Policy Making from Soviet View n.d. (Box-folder 28:4)
  - American Recognition of Russia 1951; n.d. (Box-folder 28:5)
  - Appeals of Communism in the Third World 1987 (Box-folder 28:6)
  - Baltic States Soviet Takeover 1940; 1959; 1989 (Box-folder 28:7)
  - Brezhnev 1980 (Box-folder 28:8)
  - China and Russia 1960; 1964; n.d. (Box-folder 28:9)
  - CIA 1982 (Box-folder 28:10)
  - Civil War 1951; n.d. (Box-folder 28:11)
  - Class Systems and Mobility 1963; 1976 (Box-folder 28:12)
  - Communist International Front n.d. (Box-folder 28:13)
  - Nineteenth and Twenty-Third Congress 1967 (Box-folder 28:14)
  - Conquest of the Borderlands 1958-1959 (Box-folder 28:15)
  - Courts, Laws 1965; n.d. (Box-folder 28:16)
  - Democracy 1958; 1963 (Box-folder 28:17)
  - Dissent 1989 (Box-folder 28:18)
  - Russian Duma 1963 (Box-folder 28:19)
  - Far East 1960; n.d. (Box-folder 28:20)
  - Economics 1951 (Box-folder 28:21)
  - Education 1956; 1963 (Box-folder 28:22)
  - Espionage n.d. (Box-folder 28:23)
  - Ethiopa 1985 July 12 (Box-folder 28:24)
  - Failure of Communism n.d. (Box-folder 28:25)
  - Family, Marriage, Sex 1965 (Box-folder 28:26)
  - Finland-Soviet Relations 1965; n.d. (Box-folder 28:27)
  - French-Soviet Relations 1964 (Box-folder 28:28)
  - Germany-Russia 1960; 1966 (Box-folder 28:29)
  - Germany in 1920's 1965 (Box-folder 28:30)
  - Gorbachev 1990 (Box-folder 28:31)
  - Housing 1958; 1962; 1965 (Box-folder 28:32)
  - Intervention Against Communism 1983 (Box-folder 28:33)
  - Iran 1965 (Box-folder 28:34)
  - Jews 1963 (Box-folder 28:35)
  - Khrushchev's Virgin Lands Program 1965 (Box-folder 28:36)
  - Labor 1965 (Box-folder 28:37)
  - Latin America 1984; n.d. (Box-folder 28:38)
  - Literature 1962; 1990 (Box-folder 28:39)
  - Management 1963 (Box-folder 28:40)
  - Medecine in the Soviet Union 1957; 1963 (Box-folder 28:41)
  - Minorities (Gypsies) n.d. (Box-folder 28:42)
  - Music 1954; n.d. (Box-folder 28:43)
  - National Character of Russia n.d. (Box-folder 28:44)
  - Peace 1960 (Box-folder 28:45)
  - Peter the Great 1951; 1960 (Box-folder 28:46)
  - Police 1958; n.d. (Box-folder 28:47)
  - Popular Front 1958 (Box-folder 28:48)
  - Propaganda 1955; n.d. (Box-folder 28:49)
  - Reforms Since 1953 n.d. (Box-folder 28:50)
  - Religion 1963; 1965 (Box-folder 28:51)
  - Revolutionaries 1955; 1963; 1964; n.d. (Box-folder 29:1)
  - Role of the Military n.d. (Box-folder 29:2)
  - Russian History 1590-1680 1950 (Box-folder 29:3)
  - Science 1953 (Box-folder 29:4)
  - Spanish Civil War 1951; n.d. (Box-folder 29:5)
  - Soviet-American Relations 1951; 1960; 1964; n.d. (Box-folder 29:6)
  - Soviet Central Asia 1963 (Box-folder 29:7)
  - Soviet Interest in Asia 1963 (Box-folder 29:8)
  - Soviet Trade Policy 1957 (Box-folder 29:9)
  - Soviet Trade Unions 1963 (Box-folder 29:10)
  - Tsarist Foreign Policy n.d. (Box-folder 29:11)
  - Turkey 1959: 1962 (Box-folder 29:12)
  - Young Communist League 1963 (Box-folder 29:13)
  - Youth 1964; n.d. (Box-folder 29:14)
  - Yugoslavia 1956 (Box-folder 29:15)
  - Women 1985 (Box-folder 29:16)
- Series VII Tips on Aacdemics for Students
  - Bibliographies n.d. (Box-folder 30:1)
  - How To Find Archives 1963-1977 (Box-folder 30:2)
  - How To Get a Fellowship 1969-1990 (Box-folder 30:3)
  - How To Get Published 1977; 1979 (Box-folder 30:4)
  - How To Research 1973 (Box-folder 30:5)
  - How To Teach 1971-1979 (Box-folder 30:6)
  - Research Tools 1975-1990 (Box-folder 30:7)
- Series VIII Correspondence and Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence; Hammond to Evans 1985-1986 (Box-folder 30:8)
  - Correspondence-miscellaneous 1968; 1984; 1987 (Box-folder 30:9)
  - Correspondence: Reference letter for Evans n.d. (Box-folder 30:10)